paperchase.com 2019-06-22

# Privacy Policy

## OUR PRIVACY PROMISE

  * You choose - you decide how you want to hear from us and you can change your mind at any time
  * We’ll protect – we’ll keep your data safe, won’t sell it to any third parties and won’t keep anything longer than necessary

## OUR PRIVACY POLICY

This privacy policy sets out how Paperchase uses and protects any information that you give Paperchase when you use this website, shop in our stores or are a member of the Treat Me loyalty scheme. 

At Paperchase, we are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. Paperchase may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. We’ll notify you of any significant changes but you should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

When Paperchase collect and process your personal data we are doing so on our own behalf, and not on behalf of any third parties. This means that Paperchase Products Limited is termed a data controller under the terms of data protection legislation. 

## THE LEGAL BASES

The law on data protection sets out a number of reasons for which a company may collect and process your personal data including:

  * Consent – for example, where you have ticked a box to receive emails
  * Contractual obligations – for example, where we need your data to fulfil our contract with you
  * Legal compliance – for example, where the law requires us to
  * Legitimate interest – where we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not impact your rights, freedoms or interests – for example, the operation of the Treat Me loyalty scheme

## WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We may collect the following information:

  * name
  * contact information including email address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

**Back to top**

* * *

## PURPOSE OF PERSONAL DATA PROCESSING 

**Activity** | **Purpose of processing** | **Lawful basis**  
---|---|---  
Signing up for a Treat Me card in-store | Setting up and dealing with your loyalty scheme account and sending you updates on your account, treats and promotions related to your Treat Me membership via email, SMS and postal direct mail. | Legitimate interest – contract  
Creating an online account | Setting up your online account details and communication of any updates to your account. | Legitimate interest - contract  
Signing up for marketing communications as part of online account creation | Communicating product updates, news, competitions and promotions by email, SMS and postal direct mail. | Legitimate interest - commercial  
Signing up for email newsletters online not as part of account creation | Communicating product updates, news, competitions and promotions by email. | Consent – gained through opt-in at point of sign up  
Completing an order form on the website | Dealing with an order and providing you with information about your products, delivery and service. | Legitimate interest - contract  
  
**Back to top**

* * *

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHY 

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

**How we use your name and contact details** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Deliver your purchase to you | To carry out our contract with you   
Send you service messages - for example, order updates | To carry out our contract with you – so you know when your order will arrive  
Send you information by email, SMS or direct mail about our promotions, products or services | To keep you up-to-date – you can opt out at any time  
Fraud prevention | This is necessary and protects both of us  
Understanding what our customers like | So we can give you what you want and improve our products and services  
  
**Back to top**

* * *

**How we use your date of birth** | **Why?**  
---|---  
To give you a birthday treat | To send you your birthday Treat. You don’t have to supply this but if you don’t then we can’t send your birthday treat  
  
**Back to top**

* * *

**Your payment information** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Take payment and give refunds | To carry out our contract with you. All information is anonymised and not kept – see our Security & Cookie Policy for any more details about this  
Fraud prevention and detection | This is necessary and protects both of us  
  
**Back to top**

* * *

## Your contact history 

Any contact we’ve had - either written, by email, over the phone, webchat or on social media

**How we use this information** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Provide customer service support and train our staff | To carry out our contract with you and so we can give you the best service we can  
  
**Back to top**

* * *

## Purchase history, wishlist & saved items

What you’ve bought, added to your wishlist and what you’ve stored in your basket for another time

**How we use this information** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Sell you things | Legitimate commercial interest  
Provide customer service support and process returns | To carry out our contract with you   
Understanding what our customers like | So we can give you what you want and improve our products and services  
For product or experience feedback or research | From time to time we may ask you to review your product or experience to help us improve  
To operate the Treat Me loyalty scheme | So that we can issue Treats and personalised offers  
  
**Back to top**

* * *

## Information about your device and how you use our website 

Information about how your browse our website and that you give us when you browse our site, including your IP address and device type. 

**How we use this information** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Improve our website and set default options for you – for example country and currency | To improve your shopping experience  
Protect our website | To prevent fraud which is necessary and protects both of us   
  
**Back to top**

* * *

## Information from accounts you link to us

If you link your Facebook, Google+ or Twitter accounts

**How we use this information** | **Why?**  
---|---  
So you can log in without creating an account | To improve your shopping experience   
  
**Back to top**

* * *

## Your responses to competitions, promotions, surveys and reminders

**How we use this information** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Run the survey, competition or promotion | To carry out our contract with you – so we can enter you and pick a winner   
Understanding what our customers like | If we’ve asked what you want to hear about we will use this to give you want you want  
To remind you of an event in your calendar | If you’ve given us details of an event you want to be reminded about, we’ll do this until you tell us otherwise. You can switch off reminders at any time  
  
This information is anonymised and aggregated so we do not identify you but it’s used for improving our website, data analysis, research and improving our products and services. 

**Back to top**

* * *

## SHARING PERSONAL DATA

We do not sell any personal information to any third parties. However we do share your data with the following types of companies so that we can provide our services to you:

  * Companies that help get your orders to you – for example, delivery companies, warehouses and payment service providers
  * Professional service providers – for example, data agencies, website hosts and marketing agencies to help with things we are not able to do ourselves
  * Fraud prevention agencies
  * Companies approved by you – for example social media sites if you choose to link your account and marketplace sellers where you place an order

## MARKETING 

If you have said we can, we’ll send you marketing messages by email, SMS or direct mail. Sometimes, we may use purchase history, wishlist or saved items to increase our knowledge or what our customers like, so that we can make sure we’re talking to you about things you’re interested in. 

You can stop receiving marketing messages by: 

  * Updating your settings in My Preferences in your account online
  * Contacting our Customer Service team on 0203 322 4788 or contacting them [online](https://www.paperchase.com/en_gb/contact/)
  * Clicking unsubscribe link on any email or replying with the correct STOP message to any SMS

We’ll update your information as soon as possible, but it may take a few days for all our systems to update. We will still continue to send service messages such as order or Treat Me treat updates. 

## KEEPING YOUR INFORMATION

We’ll hold on to your information for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected or as is required to meet legal or regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our terms and conditions. 

At the end of that retention period your data will either be deleted completely or anonymised – for example by aggregation with other data so that it can be used in a non-identifiable way for statistical analysis and planning.

Some examples of customer data retention periods:

_Orders_  
When you place an order, we’ll keep the personal data you give us for two years so we can comply with our legal, financial and contractual obligations. 

_Inactive accounts_  
If you’ve not used your account for more than two years, it will be flagged as inactive and we’ll contact you to ask whether you want to keep it open. Unless you reply to say ‘yes’, we’ll close the account and delete or anonymise the personal data associated with it. 

See our Data Retention policy for more details. 

## YOUR RIGHTS 

Your rights relating to your personal information: 

  * The right to know whether we are processing your personal data, and to access the personal information we hold about you, free of charge –[see here](https://www.paperchase.com/en_gb/SubjectAccessRequest/)
  * The right to be informed – you have the right to be told about the collection and use of the personal data you provide. This privacy policy sets out the purpose for which we process your personal data and how long we will keep your data.
  * The right to correct personal data when incorrect, out of date or incomplete. This can be done by contacting our Customer Service team on 0203 322 4788 or contacting them online 
  * The right that we delete your data, stop collecting or processing it, in some circumstances. This can be done by contacting our Customer Service team on 0203 322 4788 or contacting them online and requesting for your data to be deleted. At this point, we will look at your request and inform you of our decision within 28 days. 
  * The right to stop direct marketing messages (through specific or all channels). This can be done by logging into your online account and updating your marketing preferences, using the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any promotional email sent from Paperchase (this option will only stop you from receiving promotional emails from Paperchase), or by contacting our Customer Service team on 0203 322 4788 or contacting them [online](https://www.paperchase.com/en_gb/contact/). We aim to stop sending you any marketing messages (through specific or all channels) within 28 days of your request.
  * The right to withdraw consent for any consent-based processing. This can be done by contacting our Customer Service team on 0203 322 4788 or contacting them [online](https://www.paperchase.com/en_gb/contact/). 
  * The right to complain to your data protection regulator – in the UK, the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/)

## COOKIES

We use cookies on our website – for more information please see our [Security & Cookies Policy](https://www.paperchase.com/en_gb/security-and-cookies/)

## HOW TO CONTACT US

We hope this Privacy Policy has been helpful in explaining how we use your personal data and your rights. If you have any questions that haven’t been covered please contact our Customer Service team on 0203 322 4788 or email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

This policy is regularly reviewed and any major changes will be communicated directly to our customers.

Last updated 18/05/2018 .
